

Giorgio Garofalo

Software Engineer & UI designer

• Cesena (FC), Italy

ළු github.com/iamgio ළ iamgio.eu 🖾 giorgiogarofalo02@gmail.com 📊 giorgio-garofalo

ABOUT

As a creative mind that fell in love with programming at the age of 8, I consider writing code as a form of art which lets everyone create their own little universe.

My commitment to detail mixed with an ever-evolving aesthetic sensibility drives me to provide the most pleasant user experience while keeping a clean and organized codebase for both mobile and desktop applications.

EDUCATION

Computer Science and Engineering

Università di Bologna • Cesena (FC), Italy 2021 - Current

EXPERIENCE

Open source

Open source project manager & developer

August 2016 - Current

https://github.com/iamgio

Developing, managing and maintaining multiple popular open source projects, mainly software and libraries written in Java and Kotlin, such as my own esoteric programming language Pikt.

Kigal Services

Flutter Developer & UI designer

September 2020 - July 2021

Designed, developed and published a hybrid Android & iOS food delivery application for a local

Developed a company-wide package of reusable UI components.

SKILLS

Thorough ability to:

- Design modern, appealing, consistent and user-friendly mobile and desktop user interfaces and translate them into code using Flutter, SwiftUI and JavaFX;
- Write clean, elegant, maintainable and efficient object-oriented code;
- Handle full software development life cycle and project management;
- · Adopt architectural patterns (MVC, MVVM, MV) and design patterns to enhance scalability;
- · Identify and implement platform-aware features and widgets;
- · Develop and maintain both general-purpose and company-wide libraries and packages;
- Use Git and GitHub for version control;
- · Work collaboratively in a team, contributing to a productive work environment;
- · Stay updated with the latest industry trends through continuous learning.

STACK Languages Java Since 2015 Kotlin Since 2017 **Dart** Since 2020 Swift Since 2023 **JavaScript** Since 2020 HTML & CSS Since 2019 SQL Since 2023 C++ Since 2021 C# Since 2023 **Frameworks** JavaFX Since 2017 **Flutter** Since 2020 **SwiftUI** Since 2023 **OpenGL** Since 2023 **Tools** Figma

LANGUAGE SKILLS **Italian**Native proficiency

Since 2020

Git Since 2016

EnglishFull professional proficiency

SpanishElementary proficiency

NorwegianElementary proficiency